<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://braunm.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://braunm.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-13T13:47:59-05:00</updated><id>https://braunm.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Michael Braun</title><subtitle>Michael Braun, Associate Professor of Marketing, SMU Cox School of Business</subtitle><entry><title type="html">test post</title><link href="https://braunm.github.io/test%20category/2024/05/13/post-test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="test post" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://braunm.github.io/test%20category/2024/05/13/post-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://braunm.github.io/test%20category/2024/05/13/post-test.html"><![CDATA[<p>Test post excerpt.</p>

<hr />

<p>Rest of post.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Test Category" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test post excerpt.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I use emacs</title><link href="https://braunm.github.io/computing/2024/01/05/emacs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I use emacs" /><published>2024-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://braunm.github.io/computing/2024/01/05/emacs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://braunm.github.io/computing/2024/01/05/emacs.html"><![CDATA[<p>I write <em>everything</em> in Emacs: code, reviews, manuscripts, lecture slides, and even recommendation letters.</p>

<hr />

<p>Specifically, I use <a href="http://aquamacs.org">Aquamacs Emacs</a>, an emacs port for MacOS.  GNU Emacs has been around since 1985, so it is just plain <strong>solid</strong>, with a huge user base for support, and thousands of packages and modes that can do anything from syntax highlighting of your favorite programming language (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ess-r-mode</code>) to psychotherapy (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">doctor</code>).  By using the same program for ever a fully-featured platform, I can use the same program (and thus, the same keybindings) for everything I do.</p>

<p>Emacs is easy to use.  <strong>Configuring</strong> Emacs can be hard.  Someday I will post my configuration file, which has evolved quite a bit over the last decade.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Computing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I write everything in Emacs: code, reviews, manuscripts, lecture slides, and even recommendation letters.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My LaTeX setup</title><link href="https://braunm.github.io/computing/2023/12/01/latex.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My LaTeX setup" /><published>2023-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://braunm.github.io/computing/2023/12/01/latex</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://braunm.github.io/computing/2023/12/01/latex.html"><![CDATA[<p>I write my research papers directly in Emacs, marked up with <a href="www.latex-project.org">LaTeX</a>. The <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/">AuCTeX</a> Emacs package provides lots of time-saving functions, macros, and keymaps that have become so automatic to me that I can just focus on the writing.</p>

<hr />

<ul>
  <li>I compile my LaTeX documents with <a href="www.luatex.org">LuaTeX</a> (instead of pdfTeX) for a few reasons:
    <ul>
      <li>With <a href="fontspec">fontspec</a> and <a href="unicode-math">unicode-math</a>, I can create documents using any installed font, rather than being limited to fonts provided in LaTeX packages.</li>
      <li>Sometimes there is a need to run calculations as part of the document, such as when drawing figures using <a href="tikz">TikZ</a>.</li>
      <li>Some LaTeX packages require LuaTeX.  An example is lua-check-hyphen, which generates a list of all hyphenated words in the document, so I can confirm that they are hyphenated at the right places.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>The <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/manual/preview-latex.htmlpackage">preview-latex</a> (now included in AuCTeX) embeds compiled chunks of rendered LaTeX (e.g., math symbols and equations) directly in the emacs frame. That way I can see the all of the content – text and math – together in the same frame I am writing in, without having to glance to the output pdf.</li>
  <li>Reference management:  I use <a href="biber">biber</a> (http://biblatex-biber.sourceforge.net){:xn} and  <a href="biblatex">biblatex</a>  to insert citations and create bibliographies. Biblatex is designed to be more flexible and customizable than bibtex,  but my references are stored in bibtex format. My bibtex database (which I maintain using <a href="https://bibdesk.sourceforge.io">BibDesk</a> contains 1,800 references (and in most cases, pdfs) of academic papers I have downloaded, read, intend to read, intended to read, or otherwise needed for some reason, collected since I was a graduate student. I write <em>everything</em> in Emacs: code, reviews, manuscripts, lecture slides, and even recommendation letters.  Specifically, I use <a href="http://aquamacs.org">Aquamacs Emacs</a>, an emacs port for MacOS.  GNU Emacs has been around since 1985, so it is just plain <strong>solid</strong>, with a huge user base for support, and thousands of packages and modes that can do anything from syntax highlighting of your favorite programming language (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ess-r-mode</code>) to psychotherapy (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">doctor</code>).  By using the same program for ever a fully-featured platform, I can use the same program (and thus, the same keybindings) for everything I do.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Computing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I write my research papers directly in Emacs, marked up with LaTeX. The AuCTeX Emacs package provides lots of time-saving functions, macros, and keymaps that have become so automatic to me that I can just focus on the writing.]]></summary></entry></feed>